“When you are lonely, Mawusi, look for a gang. We are stronger together.”
Nunyati had told me London was a city of travellers. A place where you could always find one of your kind.
I looked around, then I noticed a large group of birds perched on the steps of the square. They seemed to know their way around and they were singing.
“Sing, Mawusi. Wherever you are, singing will bring you closer to home.”
A grey dove was leading the choir, inviting passers-by to join in. I went closer.
“A migrant!” Shouted a blackbird, and they all turned towards me.
It was good not to feel invisible anymore.
But then, I noticed the song,
“Migrants go home. Migrants go home.”
They were chanting, over and over, louder and louder. When they saw me, their excitement grew.
Next to the choir, one large pigeon was addressing the crowd from a pedestal.
“The Great Replacement is happening!
While you are hard at work, cuckoos from Africa are coming to your nests, kicking out your eggs to replace them by their own.
And don’t think it’s only the cuckoos! Do the maths: we pigeons lay two eggs a year. A sand martin lays five eggs per season. Warblers up to nine eggs!
I’m asking you, my friends. Do you really want to live in a city you don’t recognise anymore, that has been taken over by these parasites?
Migrants take our nests, our food, our heritage. In ten years, if we don’t do anything, there will be no pigeons. Is this what you want?”
Then he looked at me. They all looked at me.
I froze. They started marching in my direction, but I could not move.
Their voices surrounded me, muffled, distant like in a bad dream.
And then, I heard someone whispering in my ear: it was a very old crow, and she looked angry.
“What are you still doing there, you idiot? Fly, birdie, fly for your life.”
So I did. I flew as fast as I could.
I could still hear them behind me, they were big birds, but fear makes you faster.
I flew until my wings ached, going in circles over the city, desperately trying to spot a place to hide, to find a way out in that ocean of concrete.
Finally, I landed in a dark little alleyway, exhausted.
It smelled like garbage, but at least it was quiet and I was alone.